Curriculum Vitae



Michelle Falzon

7, Triq il-Fjorin, Swieqi, SWQ 2602, Malta

+356 7909 9612

michelle_falzon@hotmail.com

About

Hello! I am an artificial intelligence graduate from the University of Malta. I am a hard working individual who always strives to improve my skills. I have worked in the iGaming industry for almost two years.

Throughout my time at Raketech, I learnt to adapt quickly, think creatively and manage a team. Within a few months in the company, I was leading a small team with various skills and backgrounds. Our aim was to improve a small network of sites by making them engaging to our target audience, fast, responsive and increase their overall SEO performance.

The rest of my experience, though unrelated to my line of work, helped me understand the qualities needed to be a good leader and team player. I have also tried my hand at voluntary work which was incredibly rewarding. It was through this type of work that I learned proper time management and coping with new challenges.

In my free time I enjoy fencing and taking part in theatrical performances, as well as, reading and gardening.

I believe that teamwork, organization, having a willingness to learn and good time management are the keys to success!

Experience

09/2017 - Present

Web Developer and Team Performance Coordinator - Raketech

- Languages used: React, Vanilla Javascript with jQuery, SQL, PHP, HTML and CSS
- Developing an internal tool for simplifying the visualization of site metrics and Search Engine Optimization (SEO) health and recommending websites from which purchased links would improve the site's overall rank metrics.
 This involved the use of third party APIs, React libraries, messaging queues (RabbitMQ), database design and management.
- Maintaining, designing and developing new features for loan affiliation websites with a focus on SEO
- Overseeing team performance and coordinating tasks (both in-house and with freelancers)
- Managing the acquisition of affiliation links for each site

- Maintaining the overall SEO health of the sites by abiding to the guidelines set by Google
- · Working with third parties to optimize products and sales
- Minor server side jobs such as creating CRON jobs and service files
- Winner of the Ownership and Teamwork Raketech Awards
- Winner of the Innovation Day Award

07/2016 - 09/2016 Intern Front End Developer - Betsson Group

- Bug fixing
- Minor testing
- Styling of new features

10/2015 - 12/2017 Attendant I.T. Services - University of Malta

- Supervising computer labs
- Troubleshooting

09/2015 - 03/2016 Junior Clerk - HLB Falzon & Falzon (Family Business)

06/2015 - 08/2015 Teen Group Leader - BELS

• Supervising foreign students ages 12 to 17 on activities.

03/2015 - 06/2015 Children's' Animator After Glow Events

• Taking care of children between the ages of 3 and 10 years old

Dancing, Games, Balloon modelling

04/2014 - 03/2015 Children's' Animator - PartyTrap

07/2013 - 09/2013 Assistant - HLB Falzon & Falzon (Family Business)

• Filing and updating archives

Education and training

2019 SEO 2019: Complete SEO Training - Arun Nagarathana (Udemy)

2019 The Web Developer Bootcamp - Colt Steele (Udemy)

HTML5

• CSS3

JavaScript

Bootstrap

SemanticUI

jQuery

NodeJS

NPM

ExpressJS

REST

MongoDB

PassportJS

2018 Informal Leadership Training - StreetHR (Malta)

2014 - 2017	BSC 1CT (Artificial Intelligence - Honours) EQF level 6 - University of Malta	
	 Programming in Java, C, C++, HTML + CSS, Java MATLAB Web Development Signal Processing Data Structures and Algorithms Mathematics for Engineers Discrete Mathematics Databases Natural Language Processing Intelligent Agents Web Intelligence Advanced Game Al Entrepreneurship Object Oriented Programming Business Intelligence Machine Learning Content Based Image Retrieval and Categoriza 	
2015	CS50 - Computer Science Introduction Course - Harvard University	
	C programmingWeb Development - HTML, CSS , PHP, Javascr	pt
2012	Web Design Summer Course - STC	
2012 - 2014	De La Salle College Sixth Form EQF level 4	
	 Advanced level: Computing and Pure Mathematics Intermediate level: English, Physics and Systems of Knowledge 	
2001 - 2012	School Leaving Certificate Level 3 - St. Joseph School	
	 English Maltese Maths Religion Chemistry Biology Physics French Compute 	ter Studies
Hobbies		
2008 - 2017	Olympic Fencing - St. Paul Fencing Club	
2012 - 2018	Drama and Theatrical Productions - DLS Productions/ KSU Students' Fest	

Historical Fencing — Malta Historical Fencing Association

Reading, Gardening, Basketball, Baking, Gaming, Art

2017 - 2018

Other

Voluntary Work

07/2013 - 09/2013 Volunteer - Nature Trust Malta (Malta)
 Taking care of the injured turtles at Fort Lucjan
 Taking care of children and collecting donations during the 'Kids on the Coast' events
 07/2013 - 11/2013 Child-care worker - MSSP Oratory
 Taking the young children during the homily and teaching them about the readings in a simple manner as well as planning games for them

01/2014 - 10/2014 Deputy Mayor - Swieqi Youth Local Council
2015 - 2017 Subcommittee - 1CTSA (1CT Students' Association)